# Juan Manuel Buendia

## Programmer and Engineer



702 - 275 - 6368



jmbuendia95@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/juan-buendia-ab8a0111a

### Security Clearance

Top Secret SSBI with SCI Access
CI Polygraph
Last update completed August 3, 2019

#### EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science // Electrical Engineering University of Nevada Las Vegas, Las Vegas, NV 2011-2019

Completed while holding full-time job

Technical Training//Nuclear Engineering Naval Nuclear Power Training Command 1999-2001

#### SKILLS

Algorithms
Team Oriented
Team Outivation
Mission Focus
Attention to Detail
Operation Risk Management
Problem Solving
Time Management
Oustomer Needs Focus
Accountability

#### Technical SKILLS

C++
C#
HTML5
Matlab
Quartus
RF
Multimeter
Spectrum Analyzer
Noise Figure Meter
Cadence
LTSpice
Pspice
Troubleshooting
Engineering Schematics

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a Programmer and Engineer with over 20 years of experience working in the Defense Industry. I am experienced in C++, some C#, HTMLS, VHDL, some Verilog, some Visual Basic, and in problem solving. My career also contains a proven track record in flight-testing, data analysis, operating and maintaining RF and electronic equipment, and Nuclear Plant Operations.

At JT4, executed flight-test missions as lead test conductor, and delivered data analysis for the F-35 program. I also held the title of Electronics Technician 3 where I maintained multiple RF and electronic equipment within a Test Range Infrastructure at optimal readiness levels for customer evolutions.

Prior to JT4, I was a Nuclear Reactor Operator and Electronics Technician where I was a qualified Naval Nuclear Reactor Operator, Electric Plant Operator, and Technician. I was responsible to maintain Reactor Instrumentation and Control as well as Reactor Protection and Safety electronic equipment.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Operations Test Analyst 2 and Electronics Technician 3 JT3/JT4 LLC (JT3 became JT4) | Las Vegas, NV | 2005 – 2020

Coordinated with Project Officers, Customers, and Test Range Infrastructure Assets to execute millions of dollars in flight-testing for the F-35 program as well as analyze and deliver data for the F-35 and F-18 programs

- · Executed Flight-Testing as lead test conductor
- Volunteered as Test Team member for other projects to execute highly visible flight-testing as well as deliver post-mission data analysis
- . Augmented a company proprietary analysis tool using Visual Basic

Maintained multiple nationally important electronic systems within a Test Range Infrastructure at optimal readiness levels to support millions of dollars of customer evolutions

- · Troubleshoot Rf and electronic equipment to the component level
- Used VHDL to help interface an FPGA between a CPU and Modem
- Used C# to debug remote control ethernet controller for power supplies
- Performed acceptance testing on various components to ensure engineering specifications were met

Naval Nuclear Reactor Operator and Electronics Technician United States Navy | Various | 1999 – 2005

Operated a Naval Nuclear Reactor Plant at safe levels onboard a naval vessel

- Qualified as Reactor Operator and Electrical Operator
- Troubleshoot Reactor Instrumentation and Control as well as Reactor Protection equipment to the component level
- Perform preventative maintenance such as alignments, alignment checks, trip point and calibration checks, and calorimetrics